<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on mazlum</title><link>https://mozhn.dev/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on mazlum</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mozhn.dev/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back After 4 Years: Scraping, Security, and New Projects</title><link>https://mozhn.dev/en/posts/back-after-4-years/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://mozhn.dev/en/posts/back-after-4-years/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="after-4-years-of-silence"&gt;After 4 Years of Silence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, after nearly 4 years of neglecting this blog that I created whenever I found time to write, I&amp;rsquo;m finally stepping back onto this path. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what happens!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what happened during this time? I tried developing a bunch of projects—most of them turned out to be garbage, honestly. I built software for crypto, made some decent money, but ended up losing it all due to my own mistakes. Well, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s the price you pay for learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating a Cordova Plugin</title><link>https://mozhn.dev/en/posts/cordova-eklentisi-olusturma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 21:26:18 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://mozhn.dev/en/posts/cordova-eklentisi-olusturma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://mozhn.dev/img/cordova-plugin.png" alt="Cordova plugin"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I will try to explain how to create a simple Cordova plugin, what it is, and when we need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what-is-a-cordova-plugin"&gt;What is a Cordova Plugin?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s understand what Cordova plugins are. A Cordova plugin acts as a bridge between the web and the native system. It fulfills this role with a combination of JavaScript and native code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="when-do-we-need-it"&gt;When Do We Need It?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cordova applications essentially run in a web browser. However, the web doesn&amp;rsquo;t always provide the features we need from the native system. That&amp;rsquo;s why we need to write native code and communicate with the system. Cordova plugins enable this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>